<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux Bsd Amp Unix on Liquid Bytes - Software Engineering &amp; Management Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/categories/linux-bsd-amp-unix/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux Bsd Amp Unix on Liquid Bytes - Software Engineering &amp; Management Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>You are free to share</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2012 17:31:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.liquidbytes.net/categories/linux-bsd-amp-unix/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Xubuntu 12.10 for Web software developers</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/10/xubuntu-12-10-for-web-software-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2012 17:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/10/xubuntu-12-10-for-web-software-developers/</guid>
      <description>Do you also think coding Web applications on OS X, Windows or even Ubuntu with Gnome 3 doesn&amp;#8217;t feel right? There are reasons: First, the production servers for probably 85% of all Web apps run on Linux: If you need special extensions, libraries or other tools, you know how difficult it can be to get them compiled, installed and running on &amp;#8220;non-standard&amp;#8221; environments and how easy it can be on a Debian/Ubuntu system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Replacing OpenJDK with Oracle JDK</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/03/replacing-openjdk-with-oracle-jdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2012 15:14:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/03/replacing-openjdk-with-oracle-jdk/</guid>
      <description>Since I can&amp;#8217;t use OpenJDK for most applications (see last post), I was looking for a way to easily replace it with the original JDK. Thankfully I found a good howto. The short version:
# Download Java from Oracle * and extract the contents of the tar.gz archive to &#34;java-7-oracle&#34; sudo mv java-7-oracle/ /usr/lib/jvm/ sudo add-apt-repository ppa:nilarimogard/webupd8 sudo apt-get update sudo apt-get install update-java sudo update-java  http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javase/downloads/java-se-jdk-7-download-432154.html  This should work for Ubuntu 11.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plat_forms 2007 results</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/06/plat_forms-2007-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2007 13:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/06/plat_forms-2007-results/</guid>
      <description>The results of the plat_forms contest are finally published! PHP was the best platform in terms of completeness, maintainablity and security. Also, the differences between the PHP teams were small compared to Perl and Java &amp;#8211; that means, our **Team 8** was quite good, even if OXID (Team 6) is the winning team for PHP: Congratulations :)
I&amp;#8217;d like to mention that we had almost no defects in our solution:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Howto: Dunkle Gnome Themes und Firefox/Thunderbird</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2006/09/dunkle-gnome-themes-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2006 17:51:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2006/09/dunkle-gnome-themes-firefox/</guid>
      <description>Eigentlich ist es ganz einfach ein dunkles Gnome-Theme zu verwenden: Downloaden und per Drag-and-Drop installieren. Nur wird man, uebrigens auch unter OS X, alsbald feststellen, dass man die Menues von Firefox und Thunderbird 1.5 nicht mehr lesen kann, weil der Font dort unveraendert schwarz ist. Das macht sich auf einem schwarzen Hintergrund nicht wirklich gut. Es gibt jetzt 3 Moeglichkeiten:
 Resigniert das schoene neue Theme deinstallieren. Nicht Sinn der Sache.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>