<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conferences Amp Events on Liquid Bytes - Software Engineering &amp; Management Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/categories/conferences-amp-events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Conferences Amp Events on Liquid Bytes - Software Engineering &amp; Management Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>You are free to share if you link back</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2013 09:04:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.liquidbytes.net/categories/conferences-amp-events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer Conference 2013</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2013/11/developer-conference-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2013 09:04:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2013/11/developer-conference-2013/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m not known for going to conferences very often, so this year I will do something very special: Attending two conferences! PHP Unconference in September was great fun already. The other one will be Developer Conference in Hamburg, which starts in two days. I know some of the speakers personally (the list is actually quite impressive) and I look forward to see them again. Even Professor Lutz Prechelt will give a talk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cassandra</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/08/cassandra/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2010 01:36:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/08/cassandra/</guid>
      <description>Just one short note, before I go to bed.
At FrOSCon I saw the talk about the NoSQL database Cassandra. The guy was pretty convincing. He also said, SQL joins are slow and cumbersome for some use cases (his example was Twitter). Then his slides showed how nicely Cassandra can provide the same data as some kind of materialized view that is constantly updated after data changes. And how secure the storage is with multiple backups and smart fail-safe mechanisms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ihr habt das Scrum falsch gemacht!</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/05/ihr-habt-das-scrum-falsch-gemacht/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2010 12:11:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/05/ihr-habt-das-scrum-falsch-gemacht/</guid>
      <description>Das PHP BarCamp in Salzburg dieses Wochenende war super. Herzlichen Dank an Evelyne Selak, die scheinbar die Organisation zum Großteil auf sich gezogen hat. Ich könnte sowas nicht leisten und hätte Angst, dass Hotel &amp;amp; Sponsoren absagen und niemand kommt.
Nett fand ich mal wieder Sebastian Bergmanns Vorstellungen zu testbarer Software zu hören. Im Wesentlichen basierte seine Argumentation in letzter Konsequenz auch auf „_man will ja dieses und darum muss man jenes so und so machen_“.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photos from ZendCon and San Francisco</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/09/photos-from-zendcon-and-san-francisco/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2008 18:30:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/09/photos-from-zendcon-and-san-francisco/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LinuxTag 2007</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/06/linux-tag-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2007 15:31:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/06/linux-tag-2007/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been on the LinuxTag in Berlin during the past days. It was a fun event and I met lots of nice people &amp;#8211; also the recruiting staff of Google, which gave me a nice notepad, some other toys and an invitation for lunch at the headquarters in Mountain View.
I&amp;#8217;ve also had quick look into &amp;#8220;Einstieg in SQL&amp;#8221; (&amp;#8220;SQL for beginners&amp;#8221;) of Galileo Press. The cool thing about that book is, that it is supposed to cover all SQL dialects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plat_forms photos online</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/05/plat_forms-fotos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2007 00:42:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/05/plat_forms-fotos/</guid>
      <description>Some of the photos from the plat_forms 2007 contest are published now!

 A short description of plat_forms:
Software development platforms for web applications (such as Java EE, .NET, Perl, PHP, Python, Ruby on Rails, etc.) are among the most critical factors of development productivity today. The pros and cons of the various platforms are by-and-large known in principle, but how the pros trade off against the cons in one platform and how that compares to another platform is the topic of quasi-religious wars only, not a subject of objective analysis, as almost no data is available that allows such direct comparison.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>