<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zend Framework on Liquid Bytes - Software Engineering &amp; Management Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/categories/zend-framework/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Zend Framework on Liquid Bytes - Software Engineering &amp; Management Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>You are free to share</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 May 2008 14:16:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.liquidbytes.net/categories/zend-framework/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated version of Zend_Db_Adapter_Odbtp_Mssql</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/05/updated-version-of-zend_db_adapter_odbtp_mssql/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2008 14:16:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/05/updated-version-of-zend_db_adapter_odbtp_mssql/</guid>
      <description>As people start asking me about that ODBTP adapter for Zend Framework, I will publish it as attachment to this post now. It should work with the latest version of Zend Framework (as reported by a developer). If you want to use it, just copy the files to your include path (make sure the path comes before the ZF path). Of course, you need to install ODBTP as well and add extension=php_odbtp_mssql.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Magazin: Parlez-vous Zend?</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/07/php-magazin-zend-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2007 13:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/07/php-magazin-zend-framework/</guid>
      <description>Wer sich fuer mehrsprachige Unternehmens-Anwendungen mit Zend Framework interessiert, findet im aktuellen PHP Magazin (5.07) einen Artikel von mir. Anhand eines Fallbeispiels wurde gezeigt, wie die Neuentwicklung einer PHP Anwendung mit modernen Technologien ablaufen kann und was es zu beachten gibt. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zend Framework: Unicode DB adapter for SQL Server</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/05/odbtp-adapter-zend-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2007 13:26:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/05/odbtp-adapter-zend-framework/</guid>
      <description>Yeah, I finally got it managed to publish my proposal for the Zend Framwork ODBTP database adapter component:
http://framework.zend.com/wiki/display/ZFPROP/Zend_Db_Adapter_Odbtp_Mssql
The default MS SQL database driver does not work with Unicode, as SQL Server expects Unicode strings in the UCS-2 encoding (UCS-2 contains null bytes and the driver is not binary-safe). ODBTP works as layer between PHP and SQL Server and accepts Unicode strings in the UTF-8 encoding.
The required classes are attached bellow.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>