<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Web Apps Amp Services on Liquid Bytes - Software Engineering &amp; Management Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/categories/the-web-apps-amp-services/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Web Apps Amp Services on Liquid Bytes - Software Engineering &amp; Management Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>You are free to share</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 23:28:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.liquidbytes.net/categories/the-web-apps-amp-services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hosted continuous integration services for PHP</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2015/12/hosted-continuous-integration-services-php/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 23:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2015/12/hosted-continuous-integration-services-php/</guid>
      <description>Today, I&amp;#8217;ve been evaluating popular hosted CI services to see how well they&amp;#8217;re working with PHP and how much they cost.
drone.io https://drone.io/
drone.io is free for Open Source projects (one concurrent build). Paid plans for private repositories start at 25 $ / month. Builds are configured on the Web site. PHP support is marked as &amp;#8220;beta&amp;#8221; for good reasons: PHP 5.5.1 and composer are pretty much outdated. By default, builds are triggered by commits to all branches (can be limited).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combining SOA and Cloud Computing</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2011/11/combining-soa-and-cloud-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2011 13:40:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2011/11/combining-soa-and-cloud-computing/</guid>
      <description>To my surprise, the combination of SOA (Service-oriented Architecture) and Cloud Computing (basically outsourcing the server management/using many virtual machines) was described as something new in IEEE Computer&amp;#8217;s October issue (&amp;#8220;Software Engineering Meets Services and Cloud Computing&amp;#8221;, Stephen S . Yau and Ho G. An, pp. 47 &amp;#8211; 53).
Besides the fact, that this is nothing new, but an ongoing trend that started a couple of years ago, there are three observations I&amp;#8217;l like to share:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chaotic Pattern: Wiki is online</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/11/chaotic-pattern-wiki-is-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 21:06:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/11/chaotic-pattern-wiki-is-online/</guid>
      <description>I recently managed to publish my latest project:
chaoticpattern.net
While reading the book Sync, I felt that this is the right name &amp;#8211; an explanation can be found on the Web site. There is already some blog with the same name, but it does not seem to be very active. The last post is from May 2009. Hope I don&amp;#8217;t cause any confusion.
Chaotic Pattern will be used as an incubator/lab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWF-CMS.org online again</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/08/awf-cms-org-online-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2010 19:03:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/08/awf-cms-org-online-again/</guid>
      <description>Ha, after almost 3 years, the home page of my (so far) biggest Open Source project AWF-CMS is online again. When I started working for Zend in 2006&amp;frasl;2007, I felt the need to write a version that is based on Zend Framework. Of course I was busy with my customer projects, so that never happened. Even worse, due to a server upgrade, the configuration for the AWF Web site was broken and I didn&amp;#8217;t even find the time to fix that until today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter: @lastzero</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2009/09/twitter-lastzero/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2009 09:16:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2009/09/twitter-lastzero/</guid>
      <description>Wow, after years, I managed to create a twitter account this week. @williamluciw invited me. It&amp;#8217;s much easier to write short tweets from time to time, than updating a blog with interesting content. On the other hand, it&amp;#8217;s a waste of time.
The best use case I found so far, is to tell the world about things I like, things I don&amp;#8217;t like, or bugs I find in more or less popular applications/Web sites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A cybernetic view on Web search</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/06/cybernetic-view-on-web-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2007 14:46:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/06/cybernetic-view-on-web-search/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to Web search, everybody thinks of Google nowadays. But there are shortcomings: Google has just one large index for all users. This is why search engine optimization has become so popular and why you sometimes don&amp;#8217;t find what you&amp;#8217;re looking for. A possible solution would be to have different indexes, maintained by the users, that cover the various needs (e.g. topics, regions, content quality,&amp;#8230;). That way, a user can decide to only get search results from Germany without ads, for example.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>