<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Liquid Bytes - Software Engineering &amp; Management Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Liquid Bytes - Software Engineering &amp; Management Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>You are free to share</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 12:21:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.liquidbytes.net/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The nightmare world of Agile we created</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2018/09/the-nightmare-world-of-agile-we-created/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 12:21:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2018/09/the-nightmare-world-of-agile-we-created/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;#8217;re reading this, you’ve probably noticed that many software development teams got stuck in a swamp of “agile” tools, useless processes and bloated frameworks. In their search for higher productivity, they forgot the importance of real human interaction and technical excellence.
Corporate managers and employees are conservative and avoid experiments if they can. This is why they’ve chosen a permanent position. It’s easiest to get them when they are already in trouble: Not during an obligatory training but later when it’s time to deliver, money is running out and everything is about to explode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick and easy guide for migrating to Go 1.11 modules</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2018/09/quick-and-easy-guide-for-migrating-to-go-1-11-modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 08:46:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2018/09/quick-and-easy-guide-for-migrating-to-go-1-11-modules/</guid>
      <description>Dependency management traditionally has been one of the weak spots of Go. Knowing that Google internally is using a monorepo, this didn&amp;#8217;t seem much of a surprise. Various techniques like using a vendor directory and tools like dep evolved to solve the issue. Go 1.11 finally comes with (experimental) module support and the good news is: While it doesn&amp;#8217;t look anything similar to dep, it&amp;#8217;s surprisingly easy to migrate to and use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You’re not an influencer, you’re for sale</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2017/09/youre-not-an-influencer-youre-for-sale/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 06:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2017/09/youre-not-an-influencer-youre-for-sale/</guid>
      <description>Be honest: Does the number of followers on platforms like Twitter matter to you? Even if you&amp;#8217;re above average, there&amp;#8217;s always room for more.
Social media makes it very easy to compare your own profile and influence with that of others by design. We&amp;#8217;re witnessing the effects of the attention economy. Attention is a scarce commodity so people are following strategies to get more of it, because&amp;#8230; yeah, why?
That&amp;#8217;s an excellent question.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hire the best: My amazing experience with McKinsey, Amazon &amp; Co</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2017/01/hire-best-amazing-experience-mckinsey-amazon-co/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 06:18:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2017/01/hire-best-amazing-experience-mckinsey-amazon-co/</guid>
      <description>Since I&amp;#8217;m not going to church, I need to write things down in my blog to let go. Probably every freelancer knows this: You&amp;#8217;re being contacted by recruiters that want to sell you a permanent position at their amazing company. So, how amazing can it be? Let&amp;#8217;s see.
First of all some facts. As a freelancer in Germany, you can easily make 85K a year, considering you work full time for 11 months and got a very affordable hourly rate of 60 EUR and 10K of expenses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hosted continuous integration services for PHP</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2015/12/hosted-continuous-integration-services-php/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 23:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2015/12/hosted-continuous-integration-services-php/</guid>
      <description>Today, I&amp;#8217;ve been evaluating popular hosted CI services to see how well they&amp;#8217;re working with PHP and how much they cost.
drone.io https://drone.io/
drone.io is free for Open Source projects (one concurrent build). Paid plans for private repositories start at 25 $ / month. Builds are configured on the Web site. PHP support is marked as &amp;#8220;beta&amp;#8221; for good reasons: PHP 5.5.1 and composer are pretty much outdated. By default, builds are triggered by commits to all branches (can be limited).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mocks are evil</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2015/11/mocks-are-evil/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2015 05:39:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2015/11/mocks-are-evil/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;#8217;s some confusion in the community concerning the use of mocks for unit testing. Mocking is creating objects that simulate the behaviour of real objects. I personally don&amp;#8217;t mock class dependencies by default but use real objects and test doubles via dependency injection.
Despite the success of this approach, many developers are still plagued by concerns that the resulting tests are just some sort of component or integration tests and not true unit tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Input, model and client-side validation explained</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2015/11/form-validation-vs-model-validation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 06:28:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2015/11/form-validation-vs-model-validation/</guid>
      <description>This is a follow-up on Why I’m using a separate layer for input data validation that explains the key differences between client-side, input value (form) and model validation.
In general, model validation operates on trusted data (internal system state) and should ideally be repeatable at any point in time while input validation explicitly operates once on data that comes from untrusted sources (depending on the use case and user privileges).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I’m using a separate layer for input data validation</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2015/11/why-im-using-a-separate-layer-for-input-data-validation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2015 13:23:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2015/11/why-im-using-a-separate-layer-for-input-data-validation/</guid>
      <description>While some developers seem to prefer to implement their user data validation rules directly in the model layer (or even worse, the ORM entity layer), this very often leads to problems as described by Stefan Priebsch in his blog post on How to Validate Data.

In addition to the many issues he mentioned, you should consider the following advantages of using a separate layer to validate user input data:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dependent Symfony 2 Bundles and Testability</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2015/11/dependent-symfony-2-bundles-and-testability/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 12:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2015/11/dependent-symfony-2-bundles-and-testability/</guid>
      <description>I just came across a question concerning Symfony 2 bundles and testability on Stack Overflow that I would like to share with you.

When using Symfony, inexperienced or insecure developers tend to use lots of existing bundles, because this seems to be the recommend way of building an application. Later, they wonder, why it&amp;#8217;s so hard to write unit and component tests or they write functional tests instead and call them unit tests, because this really seems to be the only possible way to write tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to conduct a great IT job interview</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2015/10/how-to-conduct-a-great-it-job-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 09:01:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2015/10/how-to-conduct-a-great-it-job-interview/</guid>
      <description>If you own a software company or work there in HR, it is your goal to hire the best engineers for your business. So you certainly don&amp;#8217;t want to mess up the recruitment process. As someone who&amp;#8217;s in the industry for two decades (sitting on both sides of the table), I would like to share a few points about how to make an interview a positive and insightful experience for everyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to install PHP, PHPUnit and Composer on Mac OS X</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2015/10/howto-install-php-5-6-and-phpunit-5-0-on-mac-os-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 13:24:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2015/10/howto-install-php-5-6-and-phpunit-5-0-on-mac-os-x/</guid>
      <description>Make sure the directories /usr/local, /usr/local/bin and /usr/local/sbin exist and check the permissions, so that regular users can access them. This should already be the case, if you got Homebrew installed and working.
Open _~/.bashprofile and check, if /usr/local/bin and _/usr/local/sbin_ are properly added to your PATH environment variable:
export PATH=&#34;/usr/local/sbin:/usr/local/bin:$PATH&#34; If there is no _~/.bashprofile yet, simply create it (see Mac OS X configuration for software developers).
Since using Homebrew seems overly complicated and you&amp;#8217;ll get an outdated version (5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mac OS X configuration for software developers</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2015/10/howto-mac-configuration-for-software-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 19:52:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2015/10/howto-mac-configuration-for-software-developers/</guid>
      <description>Coming from Linux and FreeBSD, I initially didn&amp;#8217;t feel comfortable working with OS X and I still think it&amp;#8217;s a bad idea to run a full featured Web server on a Mac. But there are a couple of things you can do to turn your Mac into a great development environment.
Install the following essential software packages  Google Chrome and Firefox &amp;#8211; Safari is the new Internet Explorer ;) Xcode via App Store (free); required to compile software with Homebrew and comes with the Mac version of git Homebrew for installing additional Unix/Linux software packages VMware Fusion (~ 100 USD) or VirtualBox (free) for running virtual machines Docker for creating and running software containers  Productivity Tools and IDEs  I strongly recommend using a JetBrains IDE such as PhpStorm, IntelliJ IDEA or PyCharm (~ 100 USD) Snagit via App Store for creating nice screen shots (~ 50 USD) Scroll Reverser, if you are working with a touch pad and a mouse (on a MacBook) Transmit via App Store, if you need to work a lot with remote FTP, SFTP or WebDAV servers, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing the Software Value Gap</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2015/10/reducing-the-software-value-gap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 18:05:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2015/10/reducing-the-software-value-gap/</guid>
      <description>Research shows at least 50% of IT developers&amp;#8217; time is wasted due to the following reasons:
Rework due to incomplete or poorly defined needs and requirements (&amp;#8220;incomplete kit&amp;#8221;);  Rework due to frequent changes in requirements and scope up to the final delivery stages; most such changes are not &amp;#8220;must have&amp;#8221; but only &amp;#8220;nice to have&amp;#8221;;  Software solutions developed and delivered but eventually not used (happens all too often);  Over-specification of requirements to include functionality and features seldom or never applied; and  Having too many activities assigned to individual developers, leading to wasteful context switching among activities (bad multitasking).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer Conference 2013</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2013/11/developer-conference-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2013 09:04:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2013/11/developer-conference-2013/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m not known for going to conferences very often, so this year I will do something very special: Attending two conferences! PHP Unconference in September was great fun already. The other one will be Developer Conference in Hamburg, which starts in two days. I know some of the speakers personally (the list is actually quite impressive) and I look forward to see them again. Even Professor Lutz Prechelt will give a talk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Howto: Install PHP 5.5 and PHPUnit on OS X via Homebrew</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2013/08/howto-install-php-5-5-and-phpunit-on-os-x-via-homebrew/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2013 09:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2013/08/howto-install-php-5-5-and-phpunit-on-os-x-via-homebrew/</guid>
      <description>Here is how to install the latest PHP and PHPUnit versions on OS X using , which became my first choice after testing other package managers.
To avoid conflicts, it is generally not recommended to use Homebrew alongside other external OS X package managers such as MacPorts or Fink. You can remove MacPorts with these Terminal commands:
sudo port -f uninstall installed sudo rm -rf /opt/local sudo rm -rf /Applications/DarwinPorts If you prefer to stay with MacPorts: There is a blog post with a detailed howto for PHP 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Written requirements in the age of agile development</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2013/07/written-requirements-in-the-age-of-agile-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 20:37:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2013/07/written-requirements-in-the-age-of-agile-development/</guid>
      <description>Many of today&amp;#8217;s agile software projects are characterized by a lack of written requirements and other documentation. The rationale behind this is that requirements change &amp;#8220;too often&amp;#8221; to be written down. Project management might also be afraid that writing documents consumes too much time of developers and stakeholders. However, my personal experience is that projects with clearly defined and written requirements run much smoother and have less delays. Written documents are forcing developers to think and clarify open issues before they start coding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud9 IDE: My first impression</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2013/06/customizing-and-fixing-cloud9-ide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 14:18:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2013/06/customizing-and-fixing-cloud9-ide/</guid>
      <description>After I could gather some experience with Cloud9 IDE today, I&amp;#8217;m in the process of customizing it to my needs. For example, the run and preview buttons seem useless when using Cloud9 as editor only: Most PHP/JavaScript Web apps are constantly running in another tab anyways and usually don&amp;#8217;t require compilation (as a developer, I know how to use the reload button).
The basic editor settings are accessible via Preferences and/or the Views menu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Howto: Install Cloud9 IDE on CentOS 6.3 / Linux</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2013/06/howto-installing-cloud9-ide-on-centos-6-3-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 22:13:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2013/06/howto-installing-cloud9-ide-on-centos-6-3-linux/</guid>
      <description>There is an interesting (and free) alternative for those who are sick of (re-)installing Eclipse, Aptana, Zend Studio, PhpStorm, NetBeans or other IDEs on each new computer they use &amp;#8211; or for those who don&amp;#8217;t have 1 GB of RAM left to waste just to run a source code editor. I used to work with gedit mainly for performance reasons, but this option is (sadly) not viable on OS X (there is a working gedit version for OS X, but IMHO it is not really usable in practice).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimations done right</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2013/04/estimations-done-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 11:20:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2013/04/estimations-done-right/</guid>
      <description>How reliable, useful and realistic are effort estimations and what are the implications of different methodologies? Since at least the 1960s, this is a hot topic for software engineers and their managers, although the importance of precise estimation is decreasing in the age of agile development.
I would like to give a summary of my past experiences, some recommendations and point to scientific research. Judgement-based effort estimation is on average at least as accurate as formal estimation models, so I&amp;#8217;m not covering any formal methods in this blog post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cargo Cult</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2013/04/cargo-cult/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2013 11:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2013/04/cargo-cult/</guid>
      <description>If there is one work-related term that got stuck in my head it is &amp;#8220;cargo cult&amp;#8220;:
 In the South Seas there is a cargo cult of people. During the war they saw airplanes with lots of good materials, and they want the same thing to happen now. So they&amp;#8217;ve arranged to make things like runways, to put fires along the sides of the runways, to make a wooden hut for a man to sit in, with two wooden pieces on his head for headphones and bars of bamboo sticking out like antennas—he&amp;#8217;s the controller—and they wait for the airplanes to land.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Architecture Means for Agile Development</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2013/04/what-architecture-means-for-agile-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 21:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2013/04/what-architecture-means-for-agile-development/</guid>
      <description>In contrast to some discussions we observe in the software community, agile development is not about cargo cult adoption of Scrum or any other process, toolkit, or methodology — although we certainly observe this and consider it a problem. The essence of agility is responsiveness, learning, and sufficiency. Agility is reflected in sustainability and quality in software and its development — by definition, unsustainable and poor-quality development contradict and reduce agility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is your team really agile?</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/11/is-your-team-really-agile/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2012 23:19:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/11/is-your-team-really-agile/</guid>
      <description> Most teams purporting to be doing agile software development are not applying the level of technical rigor necessary to succeed at it. Most “agile” teams have actually only adopted Scrum’s project-management practices and have failed to effectively adopt “the hard disciplines” like test-driven development, refactoring, pair programming, simple design, and continuous integration.
Jean-Raymond Abrial, Faultless systems: Yes we can!, IEEE Computer 9&amp;frasl;2009
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to document in agile projects?</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/11/what-o-document-in-agile-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 16:49:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/11/what-o-document-in-agile-projects/</guid>
      <description>A posting in the Agile and Lean Software Development group on LinkedIn inspired me to think about the amount and type of documentation that should be created in agile projects. It is a misconception, if developers think that agile methods do not require any written documents. Here are a few (I think the most important) examples:
 A Wiki that contains the steps required to set up the application and a list of config files and config options can be considered essencial documentation &amp;#8211; especially for developers who join the project at a later time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does responsibility mean to follow the rules?</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/11/does-responsibility-mean-to-follow-the-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2012 12:02:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/11/does-responsibility-mean-to-follow-the-rules/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;#8217;s a misconception about responsibility that probably starts to establish in our brains during childhood. When we grow up, we get taught that responsibility means to follow the established rules of society (including our parents and the various educational institutions), which indeed is a good start. Now, the challenges we face in large software projects are much more complex and dynamic. The solutions can not be found in simple rules like doing your homework every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-organization in agile teams</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/11/self-organization-in-agile-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 15:54:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/11/self-organization-in-agile-teams/</guid>
      <description>For years, I was arguing against the believe that agile teams are actually self-organizing (like a flock of birds), because every practitioner knows that there is a lot of active organization and planing needed for a software project to be successful &amp;#8211; especially in agile environments. If the management doesn&amp;#8217;t care, the team will barely feel the need to organize anything. From the business perspective you want to have clear responsibilities as well and not a situation where &amp;#8220;everybody and no one&amp;#8221; is responsible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Howto: Modify block format options dropdown in WordPress (TinyMCE)</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/10/modify-block-format-options-dropdown-in-wordpress-tinymce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 18:02:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/10/modify-block-format-options-dropdown-in-wordpress-tinymce/</guid>
      <description>There is an easy way to modify the block format options dropdown in the WordPress editor. Simply add those lines to your theme&amp;#8217;s functions.php (wp-content/themes/{name}/functions.php) and modify the list according to your needs:
function extend_tiny_mce_defaults ($config) { // comma separated list of any block-level HTML tag $config[&#39;theme_advanced_blockformats&#39;] = &#39;p,h3,h4,pre,address&#39;; return $config; } add_filter(&#39;tiny_mce_before_init&#39;, &#39;extend_tiny_mce_defaults&#39;, 100); </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David Parnas: Most of the software we see or buy is ugly</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/10/why-software-jewels-are-rare-parnas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2012 18:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/10/why-software-jewels-are-rare-parnas/</guid>
      <description>Nevertheless, in spite of such helpful articles and many textbooks on software design, software jewels remain rare. Most of the software we see or buy is ugly, unreliable, hard to change, and certainly not something that [Niklaus] Wirth or [Edsger] Dijkstra would admire. If published papers contain the secret of success for software, shouldn&amp;#8217;t we see more jewels?
David Lorge Parnas, Why Software Jewels Are Rare, IEEE Computer, February 1996</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Ubuntu/Xubuntu and Apache 2 for local development environments</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/10/configuring-ubuntu-and-apache-2-for-development-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2012 19:10:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/10/configuring-ubuntu-and-apache-2-for-development-environments/</guid>
      <description>Most Web server howtos out there are concerned with production environments, where you need a high level of performance and security. As a developer who runs Apache 2 on localhost, you have other requirements, such as quick configuration and flexibility. It&amp;#8217;s inconvenient to edit (usually copy &amp;amp; paste) your virtual hosts configuration and add entries to /etc/hosts whenever you are working on new projects (e.g. on GitHub) &amp;#8211; especially, if you just want to test something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Niklaus Wirth about complexity</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/10/niklaus-wirth-about-complexity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2012 17:14:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/10/niklaus-wirth-about-complexity/</guid>
      <description>On both sides of this fence, complexity has and will maintain a strong fascination for many people. It is true that we live in a complex world and strive to solve inherently complex problems, which often do require complex mechanisms. However, this should not diminish our desire for elegant solutions, which convince by their clarity and effectiveness. Simple, elegant solutions are more effective, but they are harder to find than complex ones, and they require more time, which we too often believe to be unaffordable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 steps to become a great software engineer</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/10/howto-become-a-great-software-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2012 10:26:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/10/howto-become-a-great-software-engineer/</guid>
      <description>After working in the industry for over a decade, this is my personal summary of the key elements for a successful and satisfying career as software engineer (and a reminder to myself):
 Contribute to open-source projects &amp;#8211; ideally applications or libraries you already use yourself. Don&amp;#8217;t blame me, if you end up &amp;#8220;working&amp;#8221; in your spare time. Read and understand The Risks Of Stopping Too Soon by David Parnas. Do your best not to stop too soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to write an iPhone app with PhoneGap</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/10/howto-write-an-iphone-app-with-phonegap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 07:32:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/10/howto-write-an-iphone-app-with-phonegap/</guid>
      <description>PhoneGap lets you write smartphone apps with HTML, CSS and JavaScript. No need to learn Objective-C or get used to proprietary C/C++ libraries. Sounds good in theory, but how easy is it really?
I found the official documentation a little bit confusing, so I wrote this streamlined howto while I&amp;#8217;ve been testing PhoneGap myself. If you got about an hour of time, these are the steps to follow to compile &amp;amp; run your own iPhone app:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update your bookmarks!</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/10/update-your-bookmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 08:31:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/10/update-your-bookmarks/</guid>
      <description>The primary domain for this blog is now lastzero.net and not nulldevice.de anymore. If you are using the old domain, you will be automatically redirected. Please update your bookmarks, links and RSS readers.
The idea behind this move is, that I would like to see some more international visitors. I have the impression, that Web sites using a .de domain don&amp;#8217;t show up in Google&amp;#8217;s international search results or people don&amp;#8217;t click on it (is that true?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xubuntu 12.10 for Web software developers</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/10/xubuntu-12-10-for-web-software-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2012 17:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/10/xubuntu-12-10-for-web-software-developers/</guid>
      <description>Do you also think coding Web applications on OS X, Windows or even Ubuntu with Gnome 3 doesn&amp;#8217;t feel right? There are reasons: First, the production servers for probably 85% of all Web apps run on Linux: If you need special extensions, libraries or other tools, you know how difficult it can be to get them compiled, installed and running on &amp;#8220;non-standard&amp;#8221; environments and how easy it can be on a Debian/Ubuntu system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uploaded Reunion Island photos to Flickr</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/10/uploaded-reunion-island-photos-to-flickr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 17:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/10/uploaded-reunion-island-photos-to-flickr/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use the StealJS file loader as a stand-alone tool</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/10/how-to-use-the-stealjs-file-loader-as-a-stand-alone-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2012 16:02:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/10/how-to-use-the-stealjs-file-loader-as-a-stand-alone-tool/</guid>
      <description>Did you know that JavaScriptMVC comes with a very powerful file loader / dependency management system? It can be used independently of the MVC framework and is (in my opinion) much better than anything else I&amp;#8217;ve seen (including RequireJS). It is not marketed as a stand-alone tool, which probably is the reason people don&amp;#8217;t really notice/use it outside the JavaScriptMVC community so far.
Why should you use it?  StealJS can not only load JavaScript files, but also CSS, CoffeeScript and Less!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The evolution of modern music</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/09/the-evolution-of-modern-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2012 07:30:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/09/the-evolution-of-modern-music/</guid>
      <description>Are you curious about the origins of some music genres? Well, I was too. That&amp;#8217;s why I invested many hours reading Wikipedia and created this &amp;#8211; in the meantime pretty comprehensive &amp;#8211; diagram with Lucidchart. Please let me know, if you find an error or you think that an important genre is missing.

&amp;nbsp;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storing historized data in a relational database</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/08/storing-historized-data-in-a-relational-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2012 10:09:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/08/storing-historized-data-in-a-relational-database/</guid>
      <description>There are quite a few concepts that deal with storing historized data in a relational database; that means creating an archive copy or journal when data is updated or deleted.
Spontaneously, these options come into my mind:
 Using the built-in functionality (for example, in the latest Oracle database).  Using black-box technology is dangerous, if you don&amp;#8217;t understand it. It might also be hard to customize for your own needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using SQL fixtures for database related unit tests</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/08/sql-fixtures-for-unit-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2012 11:19:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/08/sql-fixtures-for-unit-tests/</guid>
      <description>This is a short tutorial to show how to use fixtures for database related unit tests. The inspiration for this post came from a conversation I had at the recent PHP Unconference in Hamburg, Germany.
From my experience, the usual way to test database related classes is to use a special test database, that needs a reset before each run (drop the existing tables and import the test dump). That approach has several severe drawbacks, all observed in real life projects many, many times:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exceptions: Andrew Hunt/David Thomas vs Robert C. Martin</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/05/exceptions-andrew-hunt-vs-robert-c-martin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2012 09:56:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/05/exceptions-andrew-hunt-vs-robert-c-martin/</guid>
      <description>There is a subtle difference between what Robert C. Martin recommends in Clean Code and what Andrew Hunt / David Thomas recommend in The Pragmatic Programmer. Martin encourages you to always use exceptions if the normal program flow is interrupted to avoid if statements (or even worse: forgotten if statements and mixed result types) while Hunt/Thomas say this can cause harm (&amp;#8220;it&amp;#8217;s a kind of cascading goto&amp;#8221;) and should only be used if something truly unexpected happens (tip 34).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kaunertal Desktop Wallpaper</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/05/kaunertal-desktop-wallpaper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2012 12:03:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/05/kaunertal-desktop-wallpaper/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Passion</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/04/about-passion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 08:57:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/04/about-passion/</guid>
      <description>What does passion mean for a Software Engineer? Depends on the context. First, and that&amp;#8217;s what start-up companies usually expect from their employes, it means you love the company, the business idea and the team you work with. Some people are also passionate about their Apple computer/phone/tablet in a similar way (the term &amp;#8220;Fanboy&amp;#8221; is frequently used in Web forums to describe this behavior). *
Second, it can mean that you stay ahead of the curve and have strong opinions about how to do your job (independent from the company you&amp;#8217;re currently working for): For example, I&amp;#8217;m obsessed with clean code and unit tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wunderkit and the 6Wunderkinder – 8 months later</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/04/wunderkit-and-the-6wunderkinder-8-months-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2012 14:55:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/04/wunderkit-and-the-6wunderkinder-8-months-later/</guid>
      <description>As you can see on my Linkedin profile, I used to work as consultant for 6Wunderkinder, a Berlin based start-up company, last year. My job was to provide training for the developers and help building the initial Web frontend for Wunderkit, their next product after the popular Wunderlist app. Even though I could say a lot about what I liked and didn&amp;#8217;t like about any company I worked with, I&amp;#8217;m never disclosing internal details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Clean Coder</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/04/the-clean-coder/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2012 10:50:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/04/the-clean-coder/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m currently reading The Clean Coder by Robert C. Martin. Here are some of my favorite quotes:
Caffeine &amp;#8220;There is no doubt that some of us can make more efficient use of our focus-manna by consuming moderate amounts of caffeine. But take care. Caffeine also puts a strange jitter on our focus.&amp;#8221;
Arrogance &amp;#8220;Programmers tend to be arrogant, self-absorbed introverts.We didn&amp;#8217;t go into this business because we like people. Most of us got into programming because we prefer to deeply focus on sterile minutia, juggle lots of concepts simultaneously, and in general prove to ourselves that we have brains the size of a planet, all while not having to interact with the messy complexities of other people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eclipse is not the solution!</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/04/updated-cccs-for-php-posting-eclipse-is-not-the-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2012 21:42:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/04/updated-cccs-for-php-posting-eclipse-is-not-the-solution/</guid>
      <description>During the last couple of days, I&amp;#8217;ve been updating my posting about cargo cult coding standards for PHP. There are some examples now. Thanks to Arturas Smorgun for retweeting it. I&amp;#8217;m sure my post doesn&amp;#8217;t have a huge impact on the community, but for me it&amp;#8217;s still worth talking about my experiences.
Guess what&amp;#8217;s bothering me the most is that the popular PEAR/Zend Framework coding standard actually forces you to lose the context of your currently edited code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green wallpaper for the new iPad</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/04/green-wallpaper-for-the-new-ipad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2012 13:02:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/04/green-wallpaper-for-the-new-ipad/</guid>
      <description>Just came back from the botanic garden and brought this iPad 3 wallpaper with me (2048&amp;#215;2048 px):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cargo Cult Coding Standards (CCCS) for PHP</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/04/cargo-cult-coding-standards-cccs-for-php/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 18:50:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/04/cargo-cult-coding-standards-cccs-for-php/</guid>
      <description>Cargo cult means that you copy some (previously) successful behavior from others and expect something good to happen to you (or your project) as well. For coding standards, that&amp;#8217;s a very good starting point. Especially since formatting standards are often not based on any science &amp;#8211; life is just easier, if everyone is using the same formatting for source code and we all hate the discussions at the start of projects, when some junior developer tries to promote it&amp;#8217;s own fancy ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Replacing OpenJDK with Oracle JDK</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/03/replacing-openjdk-with-oracle-jdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2012 15:14:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/03/replacing-openjdk-with-oracle-jdk/</guid>
      <description>Since I can&amp;#8217;t use OpenJDK for most applications (see last post), I was looking for a way to easily replace it with the original JDK. Thankfully I found a good howto. The short version:
# Download Java from Oracle * and extract the contents of the tar.gz archive to &#34;java-7-oracle&#34; sudo mv java-7-oracle/ /usr/lib/jvm/ sudo add-apt-repository ppa:nilarimogard/webupd8 sudo apt-get update sudo apt-get install update-java sudo update-java  http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javase/downloads/java-se-jdk-7-download-432154.html  This should work for Ubuntu 11.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenJDK</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/03/openjdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2012 12:03:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2012/03/openjdk/</guid>
      <description>When OpenJDK as a Free Software alternative to Sun/Oracle Java was announced I thought this is a great idea. I don&amp;#8217;t like proprietary software too much and since I&amp;#8217;m a PHP, JavaScript and SQL developer, I didn&amp;#8217;t expect any &amp;#8220;bad&amp;#8221; consequences for my work. It&amp;#8217;s not like you expect any fancy or enterprise features, if you use the &amp;#8220;free&amp;#8221; version of some commercial software. That said, there are a lot of useful Java tools that you frequently need as a Web developer, such as</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google’s Sean Quinlan about GMail and GFS</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2011/11/googles-sean-quinlan-about-gmail-and-gfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2011 16:57:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2011/11/googles-sean-quinlan-about-gmail-and-gfs/</guid>
      <description>I recently read an interview with Google&amp;#8217;s Sean Quinlan about GFS and the problems they faced with interactive Web applications like GMail, which require a certain maximum latency time. The original Google File System design was focused on batch efficiency, not latency. Although the interview is quite long, there are two remarkable paragraphs I would like to quote:
 There&amp;#8217;s no question that GFS faces many challenges now. For one thing, the awkwardness of supporting an ever-growing fleet of user-facing, latency sensitive applications on top of a system initially designed for batch-system throughput is something that&amp;#8217;s obvious to all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combining SOA and Cloud Computing</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2011/11/combining-soa-and-cloud-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2011 13:40:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2011/11/combining-soa-and-cloud-computing/</guid>
      <description>To my surprise, the combination of SOA (Service-oriented Architecture) and Cloud Computing (basically outsourcing the server management/using many virtual machines) was described as something new in IEEE Computer&amp;#8217;s October issue (&amp;#8220;Software Engineering Meets Services and Cloud Computing&amp;#8221;, Stephen S . Yau and Ho G. An, pp. 47 &amp;#8211; 53).
Besides the fact, that this is nothing new, but an ongoing trend that started a couple of years ago, there are three observations I&amp;#8217;l like to share:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guidelines for Software Development Estimation Effort / IEEE Computer</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2011/11/guidelines-for-software-development-estimation-effort-ieee-computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2011 13:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2011/11/guidelines-for-software-development-estimation-effort-ieee-computer/</guid>
      <description>An analysis of 32 factors that influence the software development estimation accuracy can be found in Computer’s October issue (Dirk Basten, Ali Sunyaev, pp. 88-90).
In my opinion, these are the most important results:
 Try to exclude candidates with a high general degree of optimism as well as optimism in the estimation process Split larger tasks into smaller ones, which can usually be estimated more precisely Communicate frequently with the client to obtain direct feedback Estimator experience is one of the most important factors in archiving development effort estimation accuracy, although it&amp;#8217;s impractical to appoint the highest-qualified estimator on every project  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A tribute to @LulzSec</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2011/06/a-tribute-to-lulzsec/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2011 17:16:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2011/06/a-tribute-to-lulzsec/</guid>
      <description>This masterpiece can be admired at my condo, here in Berlin :)
I have to admit that I&amp;#8217;m a bit disappointed because they didn&amp;#8217;t re-tweet the link or reply to me&amp;#8230; but hey, I guess they are too busy^^</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git: A hellish nightmare!</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2011/05/git-a-hellish-nightmare/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 15:52:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2011/05/git-a-hellish-nightmare/</guid>
      <description>Even though I am the master of procrastination, I managed to fix 3 issues in flot (JS charting plugin for jQuery) and PHPUnit this week. Of course they are hosted on github and everyone who knows me, knows that I hate git because it is sooo different from svn and my brain frequently explodes when I see all the branches and connections between them. Every time I try to explain that to more or less experienced git users, they try to convince me from the opposite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psycho-Cybernetics</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2011/03/psycho-cybernetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 15:59:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2011/03/psycho-cybernetics/</guid>
      <description>It is always interesting to see, what we &amp;#8220;forgot&amp;#8221; during history. One of the these things is, without a doubt, Cybernetics (which in turn is a child of the 2nd world war) and maybe even the origin of computers (see von Neumann architecture), which is closely coupled to that.
While passing by a second-hand bookstore in Evanston, IL I saw the book Psycho-Cybernetics in the window, which was published in 1960, 12 years after Cybernetics was published by Norbert Wiener.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secrets of the JavaScript Ninja</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2011/03/secrets-of-the-javascript-ninja/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 23:26:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2011/03/secrets-of-the-javascript-ninja/</guid>
      <description>On http://www.manning.com/resig/resig_meapch1.pdf you find the first chapter of John Resigs new book &amp;#8220;Secrets of the JavaScript Ninja&amp;#8220;. From what I can see there, the book can be a useful reference, but it does not look like there are any actual secrets revealed. All the bread &amp;amp; butter topics seem covered and John certainly understands JavaScript.
I think every experienced JavaScript developers agrees with his statement:
 Browser-based JavaScript development is much more complicated than it seems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shades of the Singularity (IEEE Spectrum 12.10)</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2011/03/shades-of-the-singularity-ieee-spectrum-12-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 23:07:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2011/03/shades-of-the-singularity-ieee-spectrum-12-10/</guid>
      <description>In IEEE Spectrum 12.10 you find an article about building &amp;#8220;The brain of a New Machine&amp;#8221; using Memristors by Versace &amp;amp; Chandler. Bottom line is that they expect that a new memory technology built on the Memristor chips produced by HP Labs enables them to construct massive-parallel computers that consume only a comparable small amount of energy. While this might be the case, the article does not really answer the question how the software that runs on that hardware looks like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communications of the ACM 01/2011</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2011/02/communications-of-the-acm-012011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 17:29:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2011/02/communications-of-the-acm-012011/</guid>
      <description>While being in Chicago I found the time to read through the last issue of Communications. Here&amp;#8217;s a short summary:
 &amp;#8220;Where have all the workshops gone?&amp;#8221; by Moshe Y. Vardi &amp;#8211; he basically complains that todays workshops (&amp;#8220;second-rate conferences&amp;#8221;) are not the same as they have been in the past (&amp;#8220;informal gatherings of researchers&amp;#8221;). My suggestion: Go to an Unconference, although these are more informal gatherings of engineers, rather than researchers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why good code sometimes needs redundancy: The dynamic aspects</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/12/good-code-sometimes-needs-redundancy-the-dynamic-aspects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2010 15:15:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/12/good-code-sometimes-needs-redundancy-the-dynamic-aspects/</guid>
      <description>Introduction There is a general rule in software development, which says you should avoid duplicated code and data. This is extremely simple to remember and many developers love to quote it. Popular code quality assessment tools use it as a metric. Because this rule sounds so inerrable, it is applied even in cases, where it is not appropriate for one or more reasons.
Another well-known fact is that inexperienced developers like to duplicate everything using copy &amp;amp; paste, which causes a lot of maintenance overhead afterwards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free math “book”</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/11/free-math-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2010 08:54:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/11/free-math-book/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I migrated my personal math reference to the new Wiki:
http://math.chaoticpattern.net/wiki/index
It is all in German and with my own clumsy comments. Those who read it, will notice that math is a useful tool for me, rather than some kind of art &amp;#8211; although I agree you can look at it as art, if you got the time. That&amp;#8217;s why I tried to compress it as much as possible ;)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chaotic Pattern: Wiki is online</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/11/chaotic-pattern-wiki-is-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 21:06:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/11/chaotic-pattern-wiki-is-online/</guid>
      <description>I recently managed to publish my latest project:
chaoticpattern.net
While reading the book Sync, I felt that this is the right name &amp;#8211; an explanation can be found on the Web site. There is already some blog with the same name, but it does not seem to be very active. The last post is from May 2009. Hope I don&amp;#8217;t cause any confusion.
Chaotic Pattern will be used as an incubator/lab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple announces Mac App Store: Fool me once, shame on you… fool me twice, shame on me.</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/10/apple-announces-mac-app-store-fool-me-once-shame-on-you-fool-me-twice-shame-on-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2010 07:28:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/10/apple-announces-mac-app-store-fool-me-once-shame-on-you-fool-me-twice-shame-on-me/</guid>
      <description>Well, it&amp;#8217;s official. Apple has now announced it&amp;#8217;s bringing the
App Store concept to the Mac and it looks like they&amp;#8217;ll be
restricting apps with FairPlay DRM too for good measure. When we
first began talking about the problems with the App Store on the
iPhone and iPod Touch, people wanted us to drop it and stop
talking about the DRM tricks being pulled by Apple on the grounds</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to contribute to JavaScriptMVC 3.0</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/09/how-to-contribute-to-javascriptmvc-3-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2010 12:25:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/09/how-to-contribute-to-javascriptmvc-3-0/</guid>
      <description>If you are reading this, I can safely assume you know what JavaScriptMVC (JMVC) is, what its features are, and what components it consists of, namely:
 FuncUnit (the test framework) DocumentJS (the documentation engine) jQuery (JavaScriptMVC uses a special fork with added bugfixes) JavaScriptMVC (the core framework) Steal (the code manager / script loader; sometimes referred to as “StealJS”) Phui (component library for JavaScriptMVC, not part of the core)  These partly independent components (together with Selenium) are bundled using git submodules (http://book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ape: Ajax Push Engine</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/09/ape-ajax-push-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2010 20:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/09/ape-ajax-push-engine/</guid>
      <description>Let me say a few words about Ape, an Ajax push server I came across this week:
http://www.ape-project.org/
Even though the authors say it&amp;#8217;s a stable 1.0 release and &amp;#8220;insanely great&amp;#8221;, there are some issues you should be aware of. I write this in the hope that it helps others to evaluate the server and to give feedback to the developers. The general idea of combining fast C code with JavaScript is very good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cassandra</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/08/cassandra/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2010 01:36:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/08/cassandra/</guid>
      <description>Just one short note, before I go to bed.
At FrOSCon I saw the talk about the NoSQL database Cassandra. The guy was pretty convincing. He also said, SQL joins are slow and cumbersome for some use cases (his example was Twitter). Then his slides showed how nicely Cassandra can provide the same data as some kind of materialized view that is constantly updated after data changes. And how secure the storage is with multiple backups and smart fail-safe mechanisms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notification Free PHP Coding</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/08/notification-free-php-coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2010 14:23:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/08/notification-free-php-coding/</guid>
      <description>This is a reply to http://100days.de/serendipity/archives/50-Notification-Free-PHP-Coding.html. Gaylord Aulke&amp;#8217;s opinions are normally quite valuable. There are a couple of arguments (just read the comments) in both directions and to be fair, Gaylord also said, that his opinion is different for frameworks and libraries.
Even though I tend look into PHP notifications (some code produces so much of them, that you can only ignore them), I wasn&amp;#8217;t really sure what my final position on Notification Free PHP Coding is and I was not too strict about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Perfect Development Environment</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/08/the-perfect-development-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2010 06:49:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/08/the-perfect-development-environment/</guid>
      <description>This is a reply to http://thinkvitamin.com/dev/the-perfect-development-environment/
Work Setting I prefer to be alone, with no one walking around, having conversations on the phone or asking questions. And yes, barking dogs are bad while you try to focus on source code^^
If people can not keep their mouth shut, loud music helps a lot. Use the headphones, whenever other people are around.
If you do an on-site consulting job, better not keep the client from asking questions though: This is what he (or she) pays for!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWF-CMS.org online again</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/08/awf-cms-org-online-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2010 19:03:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/08/awf-cms-org-online-again/</guid>
      <description>Ha, after almost 3 years, the home page of my (so far) biggest Open Source project AWF-CMS is online again. When I started working for Zend in 2006&amp;frasl;2007, I felt the need to write a version that is based on Zend Framework. Of course I was busy with my customer projects, so that never happened. Even worse, due to a server upgrade, the configuration for the AWF Web site was broken and I didn&amp;#8217;t even find the time to fix that until today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It’s really hard to talk about JavaScript best practices and JMVC</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/07/its-really-hard-to-talk-about-javascript-best-practices-and-jmvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2010 09:36:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/07/its-really-hard-to-talk-about-javascript-best-practices-and-jmvc/</guid>
      <description>I was totally enthusiastic, when I first learned about JavaScriptMVC &amp;#8211; because it brings all the best practices you are accustomed to into the JavaScript world. That means the MVC architecture, Object-oriented development with simulated inheritance, EJS templates, easy testing, OpenAjax support, powerful event delegation and so on.
However, I often have a hard time to convince other developers about those advantages. I guess testing is the easiest one, because no developer would dare to argue against testing, even though many developers don&amp;#8217;t do it or don&amp;#8217;t do it right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to connect to a Cisco VPN using Ubuntu Linux 10.04</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/06/cisco-client-vpn-vpnc-ubuntu-linux-10-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2010 19:03:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/06/cisco-client-vpn-vpnc-ubuntu-linux-10-04/</guid>
      <description>Argh, I spent the whole day figuring out how to connect to the VPN of my current customer. The Windows client on my other computer works just fine, at least after selecting the UDP option. But it is quite some overhead to install Windows on my Linux box just to connect to a VPN. The proprietary Cisco VPN client for Linux works until kernel version 2.6.25 AFAIK. Therefore, this is no option for all users of Ubuntu 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Howto: WWAN on a Lenovo ThinkPad X100e with Ubuntu 10.04</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/06/wwan-lenovo-thinkpad-x100e-ubuntu-10-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2010 13:08:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/06/wwan-lenovo-thinkpad-x100e-ubuntu-10-04/</guid>
      <description>I could not find a single correct and useful description how to get the Gobi™ 2000 PCI Express Mini Card, that is built into some Lenovo ThinkPad X100e models, to work with Ubuntu Linux 10.04 LTS &amp;#8220;Lucid Lynx&amp;#8221; on Google (which is identical to the Internet). Therefore I want to share my knowledge with you, before I forget everything. This howto might also work for other notebooks that use the same WWAN/UMTS/3G card (like the ThinkPad T410).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ihr habt das Scrum falsch gemacht!</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/05/ihr-habt-das-scrum-falsch-gemacht/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2010 12:11:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2010/05/ihr-habt-das-scrum-falsch-gemacht/</guid>
      <description>Das PHP BarCamp in Salzburg dieses Wochenende war super. Herzlichen Dank an Evelyne Selak, die scheinbar die Organisation zum Großteil auf sich gezogen hat. Ich könnte sowas nicht leisten und hätte Angst, dass Hotel &amp;amp; Sponsoren absagen und niemand kommt.
Nett fand ich mal wieder Sebastian Bergmanns Vorstellungen zu testbarer Software zu hören. Im Wesentlichen basierte seine Argumentation in letzter Konsequenz auch auf „_man will ja dieses und darum muss man jenes so und so machen_“.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does the status of a developer matter to you?</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2009/09/does-the-status-of-a-developer-matter-to-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2009 09:41:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2009/09/does-the-status-of-a-developer-matter-to-you/</guid>
      <description>Good morning^^
I feel &amp;#8220;angry&amp;#8221; about the IT community drifting away from each other. There are the hard-core professionals working on enterprise-scale projects, then there are the employed software engineers working at companies like Google or IBM, and last but not least there is an in-homogenous group consisting of Open Source developers, book authors, bloggers, and technology evangelists. In the past, the gap between those groups was not that important, as the market was small and the technology less complex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Object property ordering in Google Chrome</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2009/09/object-property-ordering-in-google-chrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2009 22:26:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2009/09/object-property-ordering-in-google-chrome/</guid>
      <description>Today, I prepared for the upcoming PHP/JS conferences and had a look at the mysterious bug #883 of Google Chrome and those related to it. Also I read though SquirrelFish source, which is used by Safari 4.
The reason for the odd behavior of Chrome seems to be a if/else construct that is repeated throughout the source of runtime.cc:
// Check if the name is trivially convertible to an index and get // the element if so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter: @lastzero</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2009/09/twitter-lastzero/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2009 09:16:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2009/09/twitter-lastzero/</guid>
      <description>Wow, after years, I managed to create a twitter account this week. @williamluciw invited me. It&amp;#8217;s much easier to write short tweets from time to time, than updating a blog with interesting content. On the other hand, it&amp;#8217;s a waste of time.
The best use case I found so far, is to tell the world about things I like, things I don&amp;#8217;t like, or bugs I find in more or less popular applications/Web sites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>c’t magazine: WebZwoNullTurbo, how to optimize JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2009/08/ct-magazine-webzwonullturbo-how-to-optimize-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2009 11:36:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2009/08/ct-magazine-webzwonullturbo-how-to-optimize-javascript/</guid>
      <description>There is an article about JavaScript optimization in the current issue of the German c&amp;#8217;t magazine. I read it with great interest and there are some tips that need to be commented:
1) Declare local variables with the keyword var, to save time for searching it in the global namespace:
function foo () { var bar = &#39;abc&#39;; return bar; }  This should always be done, for sure. However the article is wrong in that the variable will be created in the local namespace, if you don&amp;#8217;t use var.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starbucks</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2009/07/starbucks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2009 11:21:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2009/07/starbucks/</guid>
      <description>This is how much money I spent each month for Starbucks coffee&amp;#8230; other than expected, it&amp;#8217;s more in summer and less in winter:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScriptMVC 1.5 released</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2009/02/javascriptmvc-15-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2009 10:34:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2009/02/javascriptmvc-15-released/</guid>
      <description>A new stable release of the JavaScriptMVC framework was released yesterday :) Justin Meyer developed it, while working with us on a new Web application. Some features like the new custom events are direct results of this project. He did an excellent job!
New features include:
 Env.js/Shrinksafe based compression: A custom env to simulate the browser. As the browser encounters script tags, it adds them to a collection and then compresses them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do not</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2009/02/do-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2009 13:50:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2009/02/do-not/</guid>
      <description>reverse_and_create : function(files){ var sorted = [], instances =[]; for(var id in files){ sorted.push(files[id]) } for(var i = 0; i &amp;lt; sorted.length; i++){ if (sorted[i].id) { instances.push(this.create_as_existing(sorted[i])); } } return instances; }, do_not_reverse_and_create : function(files){ if(files != undefined){ var instances =[]; for(var i = 0; i &amp;lt; files.length; i++){ if (files[i].id) { instances.push(this.create_as_existing(files[i])); } } return instances; } }  What a shame!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Validation in the MVC design pattern</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2009/01/validation-in-the-mvc-design-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2009 22:38:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2009/01/validation-in-the-mvc-design-pattern/</guid>
      <description>Hello Martin,
your article on Notification implies that validation should be done in
the Model layer. There are numerous voices that see the need for
validation in the Controller, as it receives user input in the first
place. I argue that actually both should be done in Web applications:
&amp;#8211; First you want to make sure that data integrity is given. You should
not outsource this essential task to the Controller or the View.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merry Christmas!</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/12/merry-christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2008 13:45:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/12/merry-christmas/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quadcore processors are useful for Web developers</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/11/quadcore-processors-are-useful-for-web-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 21:44:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/11/quadcore-processors-are-useful-for-web-developers/</guid>
      <description>Every now and then you read, that the maximum you need on a desktop are two cores and that quadcore mainly is a nice marketing idea. That&amp;#8217;s probably true, if you use Word or Games mainly. For Word, even an Intel Atom processor is enough. As a Web developer which usually has some batch jobs running, a database, memached, Eclipse, Firefox and VMware with Windows to do tests, you will see that the four cores are worth the money, however!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update on “Script error leaving page with applet tag” (jQuery)</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/10/update-on-script-error-leaving-page-with-applet-tag-jquery/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2008 21:10:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/10/update-on-script-error-leaving-page-with-applet-tag-jquery/</guid>
      <description>After 9 months of waiting, there finally might be a fix for jQuery bug #2349: When you hide or remove a Java applet, you get a script error in Firefox. The impact was, that you could not really use jQuery together with Java applets. I&amp;#8217;m really looking forward to jQuery 1.3.0! :D</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update on object property reordering in Google Chrome</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/10/update-on-object-property-reordering-in-google-chrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2008 12:26:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/10/update-on-object-property-reordering-in-google-chrome/</guid>
      <description>Iterating over an objects properties can result in a seemingly random order, it&amp;#8217;s always the same order in Chrome, but in a different order for other browsers. I posted this as bug #223 a couple of weeks ago. John Resig posted the same issue as ticket #883 a day later. It was confirmed in the meantime by the chromium developers and described as an expected behavior. Very funny.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ajax and Rich Internet Application FAQ</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/10/ajax-and-rich-internet-application-faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2008 11:58:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/10/ajax-and-rich-internet-application-faq/</guid>
      <description>Shall I use JSON or XML as AJAX transport format?
There actually is no reason to use XML instead of JSON, if you don&amp;#8217;t plan to use XSLT. JSON is part of JavaScript which has been around since the dark ages of the web. Also, there are very fast server-side JSON implementations and JSON is the more compact protocol, thus saving bandwidth.
Isn&amp;#8217;t XSLT much faster than to use JSON and modify the DOM with JavaScript?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photos from ZendCon and San Francisco</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/09/photos-from-zendcon-and-san-francisco/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2008 18:30:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/09/photos-from-zendcon-and-san-francisco/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple is hard</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/09/simple-is-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2008 19:31:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/09/simple-is-hard/</guid>
      <description>Check out these slides by Rasmus Lerdorf presented at FrOSCon 2008:
http://talks.php.net/show/froscon08
Yes, PHP frameworks do suck in terms of performance. CakePHP is the slowest while Zend Framework seems to be the most complex, in terms of include dependencies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dolphin Submarine</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/09/dolphin-submarine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2008 12:48:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/09/dolphin-submarine/</guid>
      <description>How cool is that?

Update: The original article on ananova.com is not available anymore. Not sure what company is building the dolphin submarine. All I got is this picture! Sorry.
Update 2: If you&amp;#8217;re interested to buy one or want more technical specs, have a look at http://www.thisiswhyimbroke.com/dolphin-power-boat or http://seabreacher.com/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Google Chrome bug found</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/09/first-google-chrome-bug-found/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2008 23:30:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/09/first-google-chrome-bug-found/</guid>
      <description>I just found my first bug in Chrome: If you iterate over object properties (using jQuery&amp;#8217;s $.each()) and insert HTML generated inside that loop into the DOM, then that HTML appears in random order. Very funny. Might be a problem with threads or Chrome changes the order of object properties by itself:
http://code.google.com/p/chromium/issues/detail?id=223</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beta of Google Chrome will be launched tomorrow</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/09/beta-of-google-chrome-will-be-launched-tomorrow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 23:10:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/09/beta-of-google-chrome-will-be-launched-tomorrow/</guid>
      <description>Google will publish a beta version of it&amp;#8217;s own Web browser tomorrow. Sadly, the beta will run on Windows only. Of course, they put some energy in speeding up JavaScript execution as they need this for their own applications. Otherwise they simply won&amp;#8217;t be able to provide solutions that can compare with traditional offline applications.
For more information check out the online book about Chrome or the Google Blog.
While visiting the Google Blog, I found out, that a JS warning window appears in Firefox 3, if you hit the back button too fast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Recruiting</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/09/java-recruiting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 17:20:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/09/java-recruiting/</guid>
      <description>From http://ask.slashdot.org/askslashdot/08/09/01/1246201.shtml:
 Recruiting for Java posts is a minefield &amp;#8211; it&amp;#8217;s full of people who should be stacking shelves in a supermarket. If you want a Java job, just update your resume to say that you know Java. I have met lots of J2EE experts at work, who would not be able to code a &amp;#8220;Hello World&amp;#8221; program, if their jobs depended on it. Also learn lots of buzz words.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft criticises Google over privacy</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/09/microsoft-criticises-google-over-privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 12:05:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/09/microsoft-criticises-google-over-privacy/</guid>
      <description>The thing is, any time you get a provider in the market that has a predominantly large share of that market, questions start to get asked about their practices, about what their motives are. I desperately hope that they [Google]&amp;#8230;in fact I expect that they will change. They will become as grown up as some of the larger companies around, so in some respects it&amp;#8217;s a predictable thing.
 Peter Cullen, Microsoft&amp;#8217;s chief privacy strategist</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google has lost some of its Mojo</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/08/google-has-lost-some-of-its-mojo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 10:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/08/google-has-lost-some-of-its-mojo/</guid>
      <description>As you can see from my recent postings, the submission on Slashdot asking Has Google Lost Its Mojo? is no surprise to me. Here&amp;#8217;s an interesting comment:
 Speaking as a Googler, &amp;#8220;some&amp;#8221; is an understatement. The best and brightest have been exiting Google at the earliest for months, leaving behind the political climbers, backbiters and the just plain incompetent. Now Google mainly runs on interns, everybody else is too &amp;#8220;smart&amp;#8221; to do the grunt work like coding, debugging, or much at all beyond getting face time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Google Making Us Stupid?</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/08/is-google-making-us-stupid/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 01:19:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/08/is-google-making-us-stupid/</guid>
      <description>I just found a wonderful articale by Nicholas Carr:
http://www.theatlantic.com/doc/200807/google
 &amp;#8220;Google’s headquarters, in Mountain View, California—the Googleplex—is the Internet’s high church, and the religion practiced inside its walls is Taylorism. Google, says its chief executive, Eric Schmidt, is “a company that’s founded around the science of measurement,” and it is striving to “systematize everything” it does&amp;#8221;
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript Components</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/07/javascript-components/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2008 20:05:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/07/javascript-components/</guid>
      <description>My blog was a calm place for a while now, because I&amp;#8217;m terribly busy with writing code (like it should be&amp;#8230;). With this posting, I want to present the prototype of JavaScript Components, which are comparable to Swing Components in Java. They make use of the Composite Pattern. That means every Component can act as a container for other Components. Together with Models, Views and a Controller (Event Dispatcher), they can form reusable widgets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yes, there is a memory leak…</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/05/yes-there-is-a-memory-leak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2008 04:49:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/05/yes-there-is-a-memory-leak/</guid>
      <description>If somebody ever said, there is no memory leak in Firefox, here&amp;#8217;s the proof:

It can&amp;#8217;t be, that a browser with 4 open tabs requires about 600 MB of memory. That&amp;#8217;s 150 MB per Web site, which seems a bit too much ;)
Safari, by the way, requires 128 MB for 5 open tabs.
 If you find that Firefox&amp;#8217;s memory usage continues to grow after long periods of being open, you may want to consider periodically restarting Firefox to bring the memory usage back to reasonable levels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update on Google Spam</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/05/update-on-google-spam/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2008 16:46:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/05/update-on-google-spam/</guid>
      <description>Hi,
We would like to let you know that we have updated our report to include the omitted details. You can read it at: http://ece.uprm.edu/~andre/insert/gmail.html
Also we have made our proof of concept available at: http://ece.uprm.edu/~andre/insert/gmail.tar.gz
Best Regards,
Pablo Ximenes
 I love short mails with a clear message :)
&amp;#8220;Google&amp;#8217;s chronic silence on all abuse reports makes it impossible to tell whether they&amp;#8217;ve taken any action on the problem, whether the problem reports have even made it to the operational staff responsible for the mailservers, or whether they simply don&amp;#8217;t care.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Spam – a new product?</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/05/google-spam-a-new-product/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 20:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/05/google-spam-a-new-product/</guid>
      <description>I know that mail logs are not the most interesting thing on earth, but I&amp;#8217;m not used to get spam from Google Mail&amp;#8230; from Yahoo and MSN maybe, but not from Google&amp;#8230; never ever&amp;#8230; so I try to understand this:
May 20 21:43:16 mail postfix/smtpd[30948]: connect from qb-out-0506.google.com[72.14.204.235]
May 20 21:43:17 mail postfix/policyd-weight[2754]: weighted check: NOT_IN_SBL_XBL_SPAMHAUS=-1.5 NOT_IN_SPAMCOP=-1.5 NOT_IN_BL_NJABL=-1.5 CL_IP_EQ_HELO_IP=-2 (check from: .gmail. - helo: .qb-out-0506.google. - helo-domain: .google.) FROM/MX_MATCHES_HELO(DOMAIN)=-2  qb-out-0506.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated version of Zend_Db_Adapter_Odbtp_Mssql</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/05/updated-version-of-zend_db_adapter_odbtp_mssql/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2008 14:16:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/05/updated-version-of-zend_db_adapter_odbtp_mssql/</guid>
      <description>As people start asking me about that ODBTP adapter for Zend Framework, I will publish it as attachment to this post now. It should work with the latest version of Zend Framework (as reported by a developer). If you want to use it, just copy the files to your include path (make sure the path comes before the ZF path). Of course, you need to install ODBTP as well and add extension=php_odbtp_mssql.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exporting users from DBMail to Postfix lookup table</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/05/exporting-users-from-dbmail-to-postfix-lookup-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2008 13:25:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/05/exporting-users-from-dbmail-to-postfix-lookup-table/</guid>
      <description>I wrote so many scripts the last couple of years that I can&amp;#8217;t remember anymore&amp;#8230; anyways, I was working on my mail server config today and found this little PHP script that exports users from the DBMail database to a Postfix lookup table, so that unknown users can be rejected upfront by postfix (thus reducing the load on the mail server). It also outputs a list of domains.
#!/usr/local/bin/php &amp;lt;?php $mysqli = new mysqli(&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Mini-Googleplex</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/05/personal-mini-googleplex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2008 20:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/05/personal-mini-googleplex/</guid>
      <description>This is my own colorful work environment. The food is not free, but the Thai next to my home is very good :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Borg</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/05/google-borg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2008 15:33:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/05/google-borg/</guid>
      <description>We are Google. Resistance is futile. You will be data mined. We will add your informational distinctiveness to our database. Your culture will adapt to be serviced by us.
 Stefan Tobaben
 PHP is extensible. &amp;#8220;PHP is the borg. It can assimilate anything out there and add it to its own perfection.&amp;#8221;
 PHPVikinger.org: Things that have no name</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dell 2407 WFP stand was stuck</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/05/dell-2407-wfp-stand-was-stuck/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2008 14:41:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/05/dell-2407-wfp-stand-was-stuck/</guid>
      <description>I was getting ready to pack my monitor up to move it the other day, and I pushed the release button for the mount on the monitor stand. A second or two after the monitor was disengaged from the stand, I heard a loud &amp;#8220;twang&amp;#8221; coming from the stand. I didn&amp;#8217;t think much of it because it looked fine, but later on I found it was stuck, in the lowest position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google employees running away</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/05/google-employees-running-away/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2008 20:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/05/google-employees-running-away/</guid>
      <description>One more post for today! :) As you might know, Elliot Schrage leaves Google to join facebook. There seem to me more and more Google employees running away and working for other companies now. While searching for more details about the latest news, I found this:
 Commenter Facebookcanhavehim shares this thought on Google überflack Elliot Schrage&amp;#8217;s prospective departure for Facebook:It has nothing to do with Eric&amp;#8217;s philandering. It has everything to do with the fact that Elliot sucks and is being run out of the company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safari rocks!</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/05/safari-rocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2008 16:56:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/05/safari-rocks/</guid>
      <description>I forgot to mention why I had to install Privoxy (see my last post): Because I started using Safari, which doesn&amp;#8217;t care about my privacy and security in the same way as Firefox does. Sadly, Firefox crashes every couple of minutes since the last update. Another reason for using Safari is it&amp;#8217;s JavaScript performance:
The results show the final time in ms for the tests on http://www.domassistant.com/slickspeed/.
I&amp;#8217;ve also done the same test on my Linux notebook (which is of course a bit slower than the 64bit Windows XP workstation) with Opera, Epiphany and Firefox:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privoxy</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/05/privoxy-howto/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2008 16:19:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/05/privoxy-howto/</guid>
      <description>Today, I installed Privoxy &amp;#8211; a non-caching proxy that filters unwanted content, such as ads and cookies. Jeden Tag eine gute Tat, wie man im Deutschen sagt. It works just great! Here&amp;#8217;s a little howto, if you want to build it from source on a Linux box (a Windows version with installer is available as well). Check the download page on sourceforge.net for the latest release &amp;#8211; at the moment it is 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flickr RSS plugin for jQuery</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/05/flickr-rss-feed-plugin-for-jquery-and-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2008 21:45:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/05/flickr-rss-feed-plugin-for-jquery-and-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>After searching for a suitable Flickr WordPress plugin for ages, I developed my own in less than 40 lines of JavaScript code. It&amp;#8217;s free! You may download and use it for your own blog. I recommend to save it as /wp-content/plugins/flickr/flickr.js, if you are using WordPress. As the plugin does not depend on WordPress, you can use it with any other CMS like Drupal too. Even with plain HTML, if you like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Gdata with jQuery</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/05/using-gdata-with-jquery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2008 06:12:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/05/using-gdata-with-jquery/</guid>
      <description>This morning, I had the unbearable desire to find out why I can&amp;#8217;t call Google&amp;#8217;s AJAX Feed API with jQuery 1.2.3 directly, but using a small proxy script. In theory, it&amp;#8217;s just including a script tag which then loads the remote JavaScript and executes a callback function (thus, bypassing the same-origin policy of JavaScript, which would apply for a normal XMLHttpRequest):
 $.getScript(&amp;#8216;http://adwordsapi.blogspot.com/atom.xml?alt=json-in-script&amp;amp;callback=someCallbackFunction&amp;amp;#8217;);
 or
 $.get(&amp;#8216;http://adwordsapi.blogspot.com/atom.xml?alt=json-in-script&amp;amp;#8217;, null, someCallbackFunction, &amp;#8216;jsonp&amp;#8217;);</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switched from Drupal 5 to WordPress 2.5</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/04/switched-from-drupal-5-to-wordpress-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2008 11:37:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2008/04/switched-from-drupal-5-to-wordpress-2/</guid>
      <description>After having trouble with the Drupal upgrade I decided to give WordPress a try. The funny thing is to copy the existing posts to the new tables. If you got the same problem, you can use this view:
 CREATE VIEW wp_import AS SELECT a.nid AS ID, 1 AS post_author, FROM_UNIXTIME(a.created) AS post_date, FROM_UNIXTIME(a.created) AS post_date_gmt, b.body AS post_content, b.title AS post_title, 0 AS post_category, b.teaser AS post_except, &amp;#8216;publish&amp;#8217; AS post_status, &amp;#8216;open&amp;#8217; AS comment_status, &amp;#8216;open&amp;#8217; AS ping_status, &amp;#8221; AS post_password, &amp;#8216;post&amp;#8217; + a.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comma separated list in SQL</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/10/755/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2007 06:42:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/10/755/</guid>
      <description>Just a short example of how to write a stored function that returns a comma separated list of values (Microsoft Transact-SQL):
CREATE FUNCION get_authors (@pubId int) RETURNS nvarchar(max) WITH EXECUTE AS CALLER AS BEGIN DECLARE @authorList nvarchar(max); SELECT @authorList = @authorList + &#39;, &#39; + authorFirstName + &#39; &#39; + authorLastName FROM pdb_authors a, pdb_publicationAuthors b WHERE a.authorId = b.authorId AND b.pubId = @pubId; RETURN(SUBSTRING(@authorList, 3, LEN(@authorList) - 2)) END </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing SQL – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/09/multi-lingual-sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2007 15:37:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/09/multi-lingual-sql/</guid>
      <description>Design approaches for multi-lingual data In this example, we&amp;#8217;re assuming a dataset consisting of 6 multi-lingual fields. Each field holds strings with an average length of 200 characters in the 4 locales en, de, zh and ru. A fallback function is implemented using the CASE expression (doesn&amp;#8217;t add much overhead and is faster than fetching data in two locales and implementing the fallback at application level).
This is how your queries will look like, if you use the &amp;#8220;dictionary approach&amp;#8221; (master data in dict_books and locale specific strings in the general table dict_dictionary, which is shared between all master tables):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Magazin: Parlez-vous Zend?</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/07/php-magazin-zend-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2007 13:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/07/php-magazin-zend-framework/</guid>
      <description>Wer sich fuer mehrsprachige Unternehmens-Anwendungen mit Zend Framework interessiert, findet im aktuellen PHP Magazin (5.07) einen Artikel von mir. Anhand eines Fallbeispiels wurde gezeigt, wie die Neuentwicklung einer PHP Anwendung mit modernen Technologien ablaufen kann und was es zu beachten gibt. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Howto: vsftpd mit virtuellen Usern einrichten</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/06/vsftpd-mit-virtuellen-usern/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2007 13:15:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/06/vsftpd-mit-virtuellen-usern/</guid>
      <description>This is a small vsftpd howto I wrote some months ago, while installing it on a SuSE Linux 10 server &amp;#8211; sorry to those who don&amp;#8217;t understand German or use another Linux distribution! Some hints may be useful anyways&amp;#8230;
The official vsftpd home page is: http://vsftpd.beasts.org/
vsftpd installieren und anpassen Zunaechst sollte man sicherstellen, dass man vsftpd ueberhaupt installiert hat:
walrus:~ # rpm -q vsftpd vsftpd-2.0.2-3 Falls nicht, wie gewohnt ueber yast installieren (die Suchfunktion erspart Scrollen in der Paketliste!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plat_forms 2007 results</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/06/plat_forms-2007-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2007 13:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/06/plat_forms-2007-results/</guid>
      <description>The results of the plat_forms contest are finally published! PHP was the best platform in terms of completeness, maintainablity and security. Also, the differences between the PHP teams were small compared to Perl and Java &amp;#8211; that means, our **Team 8** was quite good, even if OXID (Team 6) is the winning team for PHP: Congratulations :)
I&amp;#8217;d like to mention that we had almost no defects in our solution:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun with SQL</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/06/cte-sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2007 10:02:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/06/cte-sql/</guid>
      <description>I had heaps of fun with SQL today (again). Ever heard of Common Table Expressions? Here is an example of a recursive query:
WITH nodeCTE (nodeId, nodeName) AS ( SELECT a.nodeId, nodeName = CONVERT(varchar(8000), nodeName) FROM nodeNames a JOIN nodes b ON a.nodeId = b.nodeId AND a.locale = &#39;en&#39; AND b.parentId = 0 UNION ALL SELECT y.nodeId, x.nodeName + &#39; -&amp;gt; &#39; + CONVERT(varchar(8000), z.nodeName) FROM nodeCTE x JOIN nodes y ON y.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Server on Fedora Core 6</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/06/vmware-fedora-core/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2007 20:11:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/06/vmware-fedora-core/</guid>
      <description>If you want to install the free VMware Server 1.0.3 on Fedora Core 6 with the latest kernel, you need to change the kernel module source as follows:
cd /usr/lib/vmware/modules/source/ tar -xvf vmmon.tar vi vmmon-only/include/compat_kernel.h Change the line
static inline _syscall1(int, compat_exit, int, exit_code); to
int compat_exit(int exit_code); Then recreate the archive:
cp vmmon.tar vmmon.tar.orig tar -cf vmmon.tar vmmon-only Now, you should be able to run the config script as described in the installation manual:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LinuxTag 2007</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/06/linux-tag-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2007 15:31:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/06/linux-tag-2007/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been on the LinuxTag in Berlin during the past days. It was a fun event and I met lots of nice people &amp;#8211; also the recruiting staff of Google, which gave me a nice notepad, some other toys and an invitation for lunch at the headquarters in Mountain View.
I&amp;#8217;ve also had quick look into &amp;#8220;Einstieg in SQL&amp;#8221; (&amp;#8220;SQL for beginners&amp;#8221;) of Galileo Press. The cool thing about that book is, that it is supposed to cover all SQL dialects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A cybernetic view on Web search</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/06/cybernetic-view-on-web-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2007 14:46:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/06/cybernetic-view-on-web-search/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to Web search, everybody thinks of Google nowadays. But there are shortcomings: Google has just one large index for all users. This is why search engine optimization has become so popular and why you sometimes don&amp;#8217;t find what you&amp;#8217;re looking for. A possible solution would be to have different indexes, maintained by the users, that cover the various needs (e.g. topics, regions, content quality,&amp;#8230;). That way, a user can decide to only get search results from Germany without ads, for example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Developer Day 2007</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/05/hamburg-google-developer-day-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2007 13:40:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/05/hamburg-google-developer-day-2007/</guid>
      <description>Heute ist der Google Entwickler Tag. Ich wurde eingeladen hier im Side Hotel in Hamburg teilzunehmen. Die Firma mit den bunten Buchstaben will heute ueber ihre API sprechen (und etwas zu Essen gibt es angeblich auch, was sicher mit ein Grund war die Einladung anzunehnmen).
Da ich seit gestern eine Vodafone UMTS Karte in meinem Notebook habe, werde ich so frei sein und live ueber den Event schreiben. Ich glaube zwar nicht, dass der Tag heute in die Geschichte eingehen wird, aber was macht man sonst mit einer UMTS-Flatrate?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zend Framework: Unicode DB adapter for SQL Server</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/05/odbtp-adapter-zend-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2007 13:26:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/05/odbtp-adapter-zend-framework/</guid>
      <description>Yeah, I finally got it managed to publish my proposal for the Zend Framwork ODBTP database adapter component:
http://framework.zend.com/wiki/display/ZFPROP/Zend_Db_Adapter_Odbtp_Mssql
The default MS SQL database driver does not work with Unicode, as SQL Server expects Unicode strings in the UCS-2 encoding (UCS-2 contains null bytes and the driver is not binary-safe). ODBTP works as layer between PHP and SQL Server and accepts Unicode strings in the UTF-8 encoding.
The required classes are attached bellow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plat_forms photos online</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/05/plat_forms-fotos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2007 00:42:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2007/05/plat_forms-fotos/</guid>
      <description>Some of the photos from the plat_forms 2007 contest are published now!

 A short description of plat_forms:
Software development platforms for web applications (such as Java EE, .NET, Perl, PHP, Python, Ruby on Rails, etc.) are among the most critical factors of development productivity today. The pros and cons of the various platforms are by-and-large known in principle, but how the pros trade off against the cons in one platform and how that compares to another platform is the topic of quasi-religious wars only, not a subject of objective analysis, as almost no data is available that allows such direct comparison.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Country list as MySQL dump</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2006/11/countries-mysql-dump/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2006 14:18:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2006/11/countries-mysql-dump/</guid>
      <description>I just imported a list of all countries from a CSV file and re-exported it as (My)SQL dump:
http://www.nulldevice.de/wp-content/uploads/2008/04/countries.sql
Feel free to download and use it! An even more complete list (including TLDs etc) will follow&amp;#8230;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Howto: Dunkle Gnome Themes und Firefox/Thunderbird</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2006/09/dunkle-gnome-themes-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2006 17:51:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2006/09/dunkle-gnome-themes-firefox/</guid>
      <description>Eigentlich ist es ganz einfach ein dunkles Gnome-Theme zu verwenden: Downloaden und per Drag-and-Drop installieren. Nur wird man, uebrigens auch unter OS X, alsbald feststellen, dass man die Menues von Firefox und Thunderbird 1.5 nicht mehr lesen kann, weil der Font dort unveraendert schwarz ist. Das macht sich auf einem schwarzen Hintergrund nicht wirklich gut. Es gibt jetzt 3 Moeglichkeiten:
 Resigniert das schoene neue Theme deinstallieren. Nicht Sinn der Sache.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rettung in letzter Sekunde</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2006/07/linux-mutex-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2006 14:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2006/07/linux-mutex-error/</guid>
      <description>Nach einen PHP Update hat der Apache Web-Server nicht mehr gestartet. Die Fehlermeldung war wie folgt:
[error] (28)No space left on device: Cannot create SSLMutex [error] (28)No space left on device: mod_python: Failed to create global mutex 1 of 32 (/tmp/mpmtx121851). Configuration Failed Die Loesung ist entweder den Server neu zu starten oder sich mit ipcs mal die Kernel Resourcen anzusehen und diese dann mit iprm freizugeben.
Auf einer Website wurde</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XSS Probleme in PEAR::Text_Wiki 1.1.0</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2006/06/pear_text_wiki_xss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2006 16:52:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2006/06/pear_text_wiki_xss/</guid>
      <description>Gestern habe ich durch Zufall einen XSS Bug in Text_Wiki entdeckt&amp;#8230; wundert mich, dass das vor mir niemand aufgefallen ist&amp;#8230; genau genommen geht es um eine unsichere Konfigurations-Option&amp;#8230;
Siehe:
 http://pear.php.net/bugs/bug.php?id=7847 http://cvs.php.net/viewcvs.cgi/pear/Text_Wiki/Text/Wiki/Render/Xhtml/Raw.php?view=log  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teil der Welt</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2006/05/geschichte-vom-kleinen-scharfen-messer-heinz-von-foerster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2006 12:57:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/2006/05/geschichte-vom-kleinen-scharfen-messer-heinz-von-foerster/</guid>
      <description>Ich lese gerade &amp;#8220;Teil der Welt&amp;#8221; von Foerster und Monika Broecker, die ich neulich kennengelernt habe. Wenn ich Zeit habe schreibe ich mehr darueber&amp;#8230; eine Sache fand ich nur sehr interessant zu lesen&amp;#8230; von Foester hatte Besuch von einer Vegetarierin die immer ein kleines Scharfes Messer zum Fruehstueck wollte:
 [&amp;#8230;] Aber jedenfalls habe ich gewusst: Dieses kleine, scharfe Messer ist sehr wichtig. Ich habe daher unerhoert aufgepasst, dass ich jedes Mal das kleine, scharfe Messer an diesen Platz lege.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Spam – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/p958/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.liquidbytes.net/p958/</guid>
      <description>Until recently I had my own mail server running&amp;#8230; good old Postfix and dbmail&amp;#8230; as I ran out of time (and administration of a mail server simply takes some time), I had to look for another solution. The evaluation showed, that Google Mail is not more expensive than other services like GMX, but I can continue using my own domains and they have the best Web frontend. Also I assumed, that Google might send some spam to other providers (this is part 1 of the story) but not accept spam&amp;#8230; I was convinced that Google has the best spam filters in the world&amp;#8230; to recongnize spam is related to artificial intelligence and smart alogorithms&amp;#8230; like Web search&amp;#8230; what shall I say?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>